# Bishnu Prasad Acharya

bishnu.acharya@okstate.edu ● (405) 762-1868 ● LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/bishnuacharya

Trained analytics professional with two years of IT experience, seeking an opportunity to utilize data analysis skills and grow in the field of data science. While working with data, I aim to generate actionable business insights and provide valuable recommendations to help organization achieve its goals.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Oklahoma State University , Stillwater, OK

**G.P.A-3.6** 

Master of Science in Management information Systems

Dec 2016

### National Institute of Technology, Warangal, India

G.P.A-3.7

Bachelor of Technology

May 2012

### **SKILLS And COMPETENCIES**

Analysis techniques: Predictive Analytics, Data Mining, Text Mining, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data

Vsualization, Data Warehouse, Aonva, Data ETL, RFM Analysis

Programming Languages: SAS, R, Python, PL/SQL, C++

Analytics Tools: SAS Enterprise Guide/Miner/JMP, Tableau, Minitab, IBM SPSS Modeler, Visual Studio

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Advanced Analytics of the Future (San Fransisco Bay Area, USA)

Data Science Intern May 2016- Aug 2016

- Solved case studies using SPSS,SAS,Tableau leading to new findings and recommendations which will be used for future analysts of the organization.
- Translated analytical insights using Tableau and SPSS into concrete recommendations for business growth.
- Suggested improvements in concept development process based on six sigma principle.
- Analyzed healthy databases and packages using Minitab, R and company's analytics.

### **Digicart Online Services**

July 2014 - Jan 2015

Assistant Manager/Entrepreneur

- Being an e-commerce startup it involved analysis & reporting transaction data to improve existing sales goals.
- Coordinated with team & Created business models for profitable growth considering B2B and B2C aspects.
- Managed the funds responsibly and kept a track of inflows of revenue and outflows of cash to cover expenses.

**IBM India** Aug 2012 - April 2014

**Programmer Analyst** 

- Expertise in Oracle Peoplesoft including functionalities Human Resource Management Systems(HRMS) and Customer Relationship Management(CRM), Peoplesoft Testing.
- Responsible for Execution of Test Scenarios , Test Cases and defect Management and Daily Issue Reporting.
- Involved in the analysis and implementation of Peoplesoft HRMS for validating and capturing orders.
- Lead Nationwide Building Society project to promising insights of receiving recognitions from the leaders.

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

### Performing exploratory and predictive Analysis on CHSI Cerner Database

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

• Creating Predictive modelling that calculate patient's survival who are suffering from Essential Hypertension and Comparing baseline stats of rural vs urban patients & analyzing important factors affecting it.

# **Basketball Data Analytics to improve the game strategy**

Sep 2015 - Oct 2015

• The project aimed at analysis of the data of last 5 NBA seasons and creating predictive models for parameters affecting the score. It made into the finals of the 3MP competition at OSU.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- SAS certified Base programmer for SAS 9.0 (BP054703v9)
- Google Analytics Certification
- SAS Certified Statistical Business Analyst Using SAS 9: Regression and Modelling (SBARM002191v9)